Safi Siddiqui

Software Engineer

Proficient ReactJS developer with 4 years of experience creating progressive Web-Apps. I am self-motivated with coursework and training and willing to learn and grow for my career. My main goal is to be able to work in a company that I can add value to, where I can produce a positive return on investment, and where I can join a strong team while demonstrating my expertise in my skills.

safisiddiquim@gmail.com 630-639-0887 Lombard, IL safi-siddiquiportfolio.com LinkedIn Github

WORK EXPERIENCE

Techmade

Software Engineer

Chicago, IL | November 2019 - October 2021

- · Crafting stunning digital experiences for early stage companies and influencers
- Completing Techmade built Diagnostic Analysis Reports to consult clients and understand their pain points, bottlenecks and ultimately what they need from us if we were to partner up.
- Built RESTful APIs that served data to the JavaScript front-end based on dynamically chosen user inputs that handled multiple users
- Worked alongside senior developers and assisted on creating web-apps that best represented our clients. Had weekly code reviews and pair coding sessions.

Midwest Orthopaedics at Rush

Physical Therapy Technician

Oak Brook, Illinois | Jul 2017 - Aug 2019

- · Assist Patients with their treatment program while supervised by clinician
- · Administrating modalities on clinician request
- Obtain all pertinent information regarding patients care
- Daily chart and schedule preparation
- Maintain professionalism and HIPPA policy standards
- Able to multitask and ensure to the needs of multiple patients

PROJECTS

Ecommerce Site - Crwn Clothing

• Using all the fundamentals of ReactJs, I designed an interactive and functional ecommerce site. This project exemplifies the use of Class and Functional based components being perfectly integrated in a single-page application. This web-app accurately displays the uses of React Hooks, React Router, and the use of Styled components. With the use of Redux to manage state throughout the site and a real-time database like Google Firebase to enable the firebase authentication, it allows the users to log in with google accounts and save user data. The use of stripe payment is also available in this project and can be tested with the tester credit card numbers.

Memory Game

 Using the core features of ReactJS, I built a single-page application memory game that is interactive and displays the useEffect Hook in action. I did incorporate TypeScript in this small project but my knowledge of typescript is limited.

Scoreboard App

 Scorebaord Application built using ReactJS, Highlights use of props, state, and components for efficient rendering.

Portfolio Site

• Using ReactJS, I built a responsive single-page application to display my work and give a description of my career

SKILLS

Programing Languages

- ReactJs
- JavaScript
- CSS
- Sass
- Bootstrap
- HTML5
- Next.js
- Node.js (intermediate)

Interpersonal Skills

- Written/Verbal Communication
 Excellent written and verbal communication skills
- Problem-Solving/Reasoning -Able to identify problems and solve them in a timely manner
- Flexibility/Adaptability Able to adjust quickly to changing situations
- Teamwork Worked on teambased software projects

Programing Knowledge

- IDE: Visual Studio Code
- Exposure to Agile and Waterfall environments
- Basic computer hardware knowledge
- Jira
- GIT version control

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science Computer Science

Make School Aug 2019 San Francisco, California

Bachelor of Arts Psychology

University of Illinois at Chicago 2015 - 2019 Chicago, IL